JEROL GRAVES

CLOUD DEVELOPER



843.709.5911



jerolgraves@gmail.com



https://portfolio.jerolgraves.com



Linkedin.com/in/jerolgraves

EXPERTISE

Attention to Detail

Team Leadership

Project Planning

Accountability

Improving Efficiency

Risk Assessment

Resource Management

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE Molecular Biology Radford University

> Design Training The Iron Yard Spring 2017

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a big picture guy. I realize that the graduates coming out of college can run circles around me when it comes to banging out code and writing algorithms. Consequently, I have changed my focus to learning how to code in the cloud, understanding the lifecycle of a project from build to deployment and testing along the way. I also enjoy learning. I cut my teeth on front-end development, but I am constantly working on becoming a full-stack developer. My soft skills include team management and organization, project planning and training. You will find a varied work history. I started in the culinary services as an assistant kitchen manager, transitioned into medicine and my most recent position was in finance and banking. I have liked each career path for one reason or another, but coding is the first time that I have ever loved something. This is the first experience I have had where I have been elated to see my project come to life (or tickled pink to find that a project is failing because of a missing comma). That feeling has been a common theme throughout my coding journey.

EXPERIENCE

FINANCIAL ADVISOR

Wells Fargo, North Charleston, SC / 2014 - 2016

- Doubled my investments under management from 20MM to 40MM in two vears.
- Helped my clients successfully transition into retirement.
- Conducted educational seminars for investors.
- Provided client-facing estate planning and management.
- Developed tailored financial strategies for families and small business.

FINANCIAL ADVISOR

Edward Jones, North Charleston, SC / 2012 – 2014

Similar to above.

OWNER/OPERATOR

Dermatopathology Specialists, Mount Pleasant, SC/ 2008 – 2012

- Developed and deployed a stand-alone brick-and-mortar pathology laboratory.
- Hired and supervised a staff of eight employees.
- Performed all laboratory functions to include but not limited to: specimen procurement and processing, microscopic slide preparation and evaluation and frozen sectioning.
- Performed CPT and ICD-10 coding.
- Prepared payroll and assisted with tax preparation with Quickbooks.
- Maintained information database.

JEROL GRAVES

CLOUD DEVELOPER

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

Bootstrap

React

Git/GitHub

HTML

CSS

SquareSpace

jQuery

Node

Java

ES6

AWS

EXTRA

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE HALOS North Charleston, SC Board President

EXPERIENCE continued

PATHOLOGY ASSISTANT

Coastal Pathology Laboratories, Charleston, SC / 2001 – 2008

- Performed forensic and medical autopsies.
- Trained pathology residents.
- Performed intra-operative consultations including frozen section analysis.
- Coordinated tumor board proceedings.
- Managed laboratory personnel.
- Evaluated gross examination of complex organ systems.

REFERENCES



Cosma Muresan Project Coordinator CTO, ICR 202.491.3538



Joe Dolan Personal Reference SCRUM Master, Booz-Allen Hamilton 843.212.2918



Travis Hubbard Instructor The Iron Yard 843.501.2775



Betsy Hare Previous Campus Manager PM, Booz-Allen Hamilton 843.212.2918